Michael Anderson

Personal Statement

A budding developer with a wealth of experience in providing excellent customer service within a teambased environment in varying roles.

I have had a lifelong love of technology going all the way back to being 10 years old and doing some simple programming in Basic. This early interest in coding was rekindled when working with HTML during my last employment. Having then been made redundant I decided to put my efforts into forging a career that I will both enjoy and prosper in.

Now, as a newly trained software developer, I'm excited to combine my past experience with my new skillset to become an effective, enthusiastic and efficient member of Scotland's growing tech sector.

Get in touch!

Mobile:

07738931692

Email:

michael.g.anderson7@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael -anderson42/

GitHub:

https://github.com/RatBoyJim

GitHub Pages:

https://ratboyjim.github.io

Based:

Ayrshire, Scotland, UK

Languages Spoken

English

Native speaker

Danish

Intermediate level

Hobbies and Interests

- Aikido practitioner- Black belt 1st Dan
- Volunteer with Scottish Tech Army
- Listening to music
- Computer gaming

Technical Education

CodeClan | Remote Learning | August 2020 - February 2021 Trainee Software Developer

CodeClan is an intensive 16-week Professional Software Development course following Agile principles, involving 800+ hours of coding. I completed numerous solo and group projects and developed a fundamental understanding of the following technical skills and exposures-

- Languages- Python, JavaScript, Java, SQL, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Technologies React, Flask, PostgreSQL, Vue.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Google Charts, Web API's, Git & GitHub
- Skills and Principles Agile development, Test Driven
 Development, Full stack web development, Object oriented
 programming following SOLID principles, RESTful API's, Pair &
 mob programming, UX/UI design

Formal Education

Glasgow Caledonian University | Glasgow, Scotland | 2000-2004 BA | Social Sciences

Project Information

PokeJson

Group Project | **Javascript - Vue.js - MongoDB** | **December 2020**

A full-stack browser game based on the Pokemon trading card game.

- Users can view a list of Pokemon supplied by PokeAPI
- They are then able to select a specific Pokemon and view its full details
- Users can battle each other with their chosen Pokemon
- Uses a MongoDB database to store wins and losses
- GoogleCharts utilised to display the wins and losses of each Pokemon used

GitHub link

https://github.com/RatBoyJim/pokeJson

Tamagotchi Towers

Group Project | Javascript - React - Java Spring | February 2020

A full-stack browser game based on Tamagotchi.

- Users can create a username and password to be able to create their own stable of Tamagotchis
- Users can pick aand name a Tamagotchi from one of six preset animal types that each have different and unique charachteristics
- The user then has to keep their animal happy by feeding, exercising and cleaning their pet.
- Difficulty level can be increased for a greater challenge.
- User and Tamagotchi information is saved on a Java/Spring back end.

GitHub link

https://github.com/RatBoyJim/tamagotchi_towers

Gold Soundz

Solo Project | Python - Flask- PostgreSQL | September 2020

A browser based app which allows a record shop owner to track their shop's inventory. This is not an app which the customer will see, it is an admin/management app for the shop workers.

- Includes an inventory storing individual albums, including a name, description, stock quantity, buying cost, and selling price
- The inventory also tracks manufacturers/record labels, including a name and email address.
- As well as showing stock quantity as a number, the app visually highlights "low stock" and "out of stock" items to the user.
- Calculates the markup on items in the store, and displays it in the inventory
- Labels can be marked as active/deactivated. Deactivated labels will not appear when creating new album details.

GitHub link

https://github.com/RatBoyJim/GoldSoundz

Work Experience

Ecommerce Admin Assistant

Tiso UK | July 2015 - April 2020

- Updating the company website with details and images of products being sold using HTML
- Picking orders from the shop floor and adjoined warehouse
- · Packing and despatching orders
- Assisting with incoming deliveries of goods to the warehouse
- Processing returned orders
- · Responding to customer enquiries via email and phone
- · Handled customer complaints with empathy and composure

Customer Service Advisor

Student Loans Company | July 2012 - July 2015

- Assisting new students with their application for student funding by giving them advice on the amount and
 types of finance they could expect and detailing what evidence they are required to provide in support of their
 application
- Assisting customers with the repayment of their student loans by providing up to date balances, advising how best to make repayments and taking payments from customers
- Abiding to key performance indicators and service level agreements set by the company
- Between 01/08/2014 and 01/11/2014 seconded to escalations team. This involved completing callbacks to customers to resolve issues with individual accounts and raising official complaints where necessary.